我来讲一个小故事，说说我是怎么掌握法语里的词语连接的，或者
Let me tell you a little story about how I came to get word connections in French, or
按他们的说法，叫 liaison。我偶然看到 skidiz 这个词，
as they like to call them, liaisons. I stumbled upon the word skidiz and was
惊讶地发现它竟然可以代表 ce qu'ils disent。我心想：哇，这看起来真不一样，
amazed that it could represent ce qu'ils disent. Wow, that looks different, I
如果我这么说，他们肯定听不懂。
thought to myself. They'll never understand me if I say it like that.
幸运的是，我偏实证的一面占了上风，于是我想：好吧，行，我试试看，
Fortunately, my empirical side prevailed and I thought, okay, fine, I'll try it,
哪怕只是为了证明它没用。于是我把它和本地发音结合起来，
even if it's just to prove that it doesn't work. So I combined it with the local
设法把 je ne sais pas ce qu'ils disent 放进对话回应里。
pronunciation of je ne sais pas and managed to work je ne sais pas ce qu'ils disent
用作对话回应。哇！令我非常惊讶的是，它奏效了，对方
in as a conversational response. Whoa! To my huge surprise, it worked and the person
开始用真正的法语跟我说话，而不是用幼儿式语言。这让我进入了顿悟的第二部分。
started talking to me in real French and not baby language. That led me to part two
糟了！如果我这样说，他们对我法语水平的期待会一下子提高，
of the epiphany. Yikes! If I do this, it'll totally raise their expectations of
然后，啊，原来我是在用我希望他们对我说话的方式跟他们说话，这样我就能
how well I speak and then, ah, I'm talking the way I want them to talk to me so I can
更轻松地理解他们。一旦意识到自己一直在拖自己的后腿，
understand them more easily. Once I realized how I'd been sabotaging myself, I
我就开始信任语音，而不再根据拼写来发音。我的
started trusting the phonetics and stopped basing my pronunciation on spelling. My
信心提高了，因为思维会跟着行为走，而我的新行为带来了
confidence went up because thought follows behavior, and my new behavior resulted in
更成熟、更有质量的对话。别人不必再把话降到
more sophisticated, intelligent conversations. People didn't have to talk
我的语言水平，而是真的可以在我的会话水平上和我交流。
down to my language level, but could actually talk with me at my conversational
我的目标，是让你在 got it 上也有同样的领悟。我的工作是
level. It's my goal that you have that same realization with got it. My job is to
把这个顿悟交给你；你的工作是抓住它，并用起来。
give the epiphany. Your job is to hold on and use it.